# **Chris Marcellus**

Sandy, UT 84070 / 702-683-0971 (C) / ChrisMarcellusPom@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/chris-marcellus-40462874/

Website: ChrisMarcellusDesign.com

**PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:** Project oriented UX/UI designer with versatile skills and an emphasis in consistency and an eye for detail. Thrives in fast paced environments with strict deadlines where accuracy and time management are essential. No matter the field, craft, or setting, excels at learning and taking ownership to become an expert and utilizing skills to the fullest.

#### SKILLS

Technical: Figma, AdobeXD, Miro, InVision, Photoshop, Illustrator, MS Office, Google Suite, HTML5, CSS,

JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery

**UX/UI:** Visual Prototyping, Wireframing, User Interface Designing, UX Research, User Interviewing,

Data Collecting, Data Analysis, User Testing,

## **PROJECTS:**

inSpectrum | [link to project]

**Overview:** inSpectrum is a mobile app that measures UV data based on your location along with a water consumption tracker, sunscreen application timer and exposure tracking based on personalized characteristics.

**Responsibilities:** Ideating, collecting research, user interviewing, data analysis, sketching and constructing wireframes, prototyping, interaction design, UI designing.

Tools Used: Figma, FigJam, Miro, Photoshop

# **USDA Website Redesign** | [link to project]

**Overview:** A website redesign of the US Department of Agriculture's website, giving the page a visual update, as well as a better organized information architecture.

**Responsibilities:** Analyzing original website for heuristic problems, user testing, Wireframing,

Prototyping, Information Architecture Redesigning, UI Styling and Designing.

Tools Used: Figma, Miro, InVision, Photoshop

### The Christmas Box Website Redesign | [link to project]

**Overview:** This was a study on the non-profit organization, the Christmas Box where we researched what was important for a non-profit and how to showcase that best on their website through a redesign.

Responsibilities: Process direction, Interviewing, Ideating, Style Conception, Wireframing,

Prototyping, UI Styling and Designing.

**Tools Used:** Figma, Miro, InVision, Photoshop

#### **EMPLOYMENT:**

## Nordstrom Fashion Place, Administrator, Tailor & Embroiderer: July 2018 - present

- Directs embroidery operations that bring in \$10,000 extra annual income to the tailor shop.
- Digitizes logos, images and texts, resulting in increased customer return rate and being the consultant for the southwest Nordstrom region.
- Meet with customers to determine what alterations are needed for the perfect fit.
- Perform alterations including measuring, cutting, sewing and press garments by customer's deadline.
- Review incoming and outgoing garments for quality and accurate alterations and information, reducing errors and increasing customer satisfaction.

### Floor & Decor, Tile Sales: Jan. 2018 - July 2018

- Engage customers to understand their project and provide accurate quality tile and correct amount of tile.
- Organize to make merchandise as presentable as possible, leading to increased accessibility for customers.
- Keep up to date on price and merchandise change to reduce errors and better customer satisfaction.

## IKEA Draper, Lighting Merchandising and Sales: June 2014 – Jan. 2018

- Planned and coordinated merchandise layout, leading to being the top selling store for the lighting department.
- Analyzed sales reports to track forecast and KPIs on hundreds of different new and discontinued items.
- Maintained sales floor to keep organized as well as updating pricing and signage to educate customers.
- Answered customer questions regarding lighting merchandise, proper use and pricing and was considered IKEA's lighting expert.

## Castle of Chaos, Assistant Director: Sept. 2012 - Nov. 2016

- Developed a process to track attendance records for 120 actor's incentives and pay that would increase payment accuracy and save the company money.
- Created descriptions of roles to help actors understand their performance and heighten the quality and scare factor of the haunted house.
- Trained actors in performance and safe hands-on experience to ensure the safety of customers and actors while maintaining award winning performances.
- Oversaw any gaps in flow and filled in for any of the 50 roles needed to keep the attraction running smoothly without drops in customer interaction.

### **VOLUNTEER ORGANIZATIONS**

**United Utah Furry Fandom**, Admin and Event Organizer: 2017 – 2019 **Rainbow Company Theatre Group**, 2004 – 2010

## **EDUCATION**:

Graduated 2023

Certificate in UX/UI Design: University of Utah, Salt Lake City, UT An intensive 24-week long boot camp. Skills learned consist of Figma, Adobe XD, UX Research, UI Design, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery Visual Prototyping, Wireframing and Cast Study Creation.

Bachelor of Fine Arts, University of Utah, Theatre Design, Salt Lake City, UT Las Vegas Academy of the Arts, Theatre Tech, Las Vegas, NV